

# Roger Granada

#### Data Engineer

- P June 26th, 1980
- Rua Dona Firmina, 100, Porto Alegre - Brazil
- +55 (51) 99977-5425
- https://rogergranada.github.io
- roger.granada@acad.pucrs.br

# Social Network

- Linked In (rogergranada)
  - Github Page (rogergranada)

# Languages

Portuguese **English** French Italian Spanish

## Skills

Programming languages: Python, Java, C++ and PHP

Knowledge of machine learning and deep learning frameworks: Caffe, Pytorch, Tensorflow and scikit-learn

Knowledge of application of machine learning and deep learning in Artificial Intelligence fields: Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Planning, Robotics

#### About Me

Passionate about learning. Experienced in research activities with almost five years of post doctoral in the artificial intelligence field, including computer vision, planning, natural language processing and robotics. Recently, I have been working with reinforcement learning and imitation learning algorithms. I am familiar with machine learning and deep learning algorithms, as well as writing research papers for top tier conferences. As a posdoc researcher, I provide guidance to master and PhD students, co-authoring papers in related fields.

### **Working Experience**

Postgraduate Working

2018 - now **Post-Doc - Goal Recognition Project** 

CAPES/FAPERGS - PUCRS

The main activities include:

- Researching in computer vision for plan and goal recognition
- Applying deep learning algorithms for object and recognition
- Developing frameworks for plan recognition with real world images
- Publishing papers in international conferences and journals

#### 2017 – 2018 Post-Doc - Pro-Alertas Project

**CAPES - PUCRS** 

The main activities include:

- Researching in computer vision applied to autonomous boats
- Applying deep learning algorithms for obstacle recognition
- Building a computer vision module based on NVIDIA Jetson
- Publishing papers in international conferences and journals
- 2016 2017 Senior Researcher HP Inc (PUCRS/HP Inc Project) PUCRS/HP Inc The main activities include:
  - Researching in computer vision for action and goal recognition
  - Applying deep learning algorithms for action recognition
  - Integrating action recognition with plan and goal recognition
  - Publishing papers in international conferences and journals

Internship Abroad

2012 – 2012 **Distributional Similarity Models** Fondazione Bruno Kessler (FBK Italy)

The main activities include:

- Researching in distributional similarity models
- Developing algorithms for semantic similarity
- Integrating semantic similarity in a machine translation framework

#### Education

2011 – 2015 **PhD in Computer Science** PUCRS-Brazil/UPS3-France (co-tutelle degree) In-depth studies on the Artificial Intelligence field - Natural Lan-

guage Processing. My thesis "Evaluation of methods for taxonomic relation extraction from text" evaluates the automatic construction

of taxonomic structures such as ontologies.

2009 - 2011**Master in Computer Science**  PUCRS/HP

Worked in a HP project regarding knowledge systems applied to privacy data. My dissertation "Processos de construção automática de tesauro" analyses methods for automatic thesaurus construction using privacy data in order to map knowledge resources in privacy

risk management.

2005 – 2008 **Graduation in System Analysis and Development** 

During my under graduation, I worked with research in recommender systems at the System Information Research Group (GPSI) using text mining to build user's profile to recommender systems.